<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fixeds on Matt Drake</title>
    <link>https://mattdrake.dev/fixed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fixeds on Matt Drake</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 19:37:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mattdrake.dev/fixed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Bookshelf</title>
      <link>https://mattdrake.dev/fixed/bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 19:37:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattdrake.dev/fixed/bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>I love to hear about what people read and recommend, so here are my lists.
If I finish a book and I don&amp;rsquo;t like it, I just delete it from the list. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make negative reviews - I might just not be the audience for a particular book.
Currently Reading  Modern C, Jens Gustedt A Tour of C++, Bjarne Stroustrup How Linux Works, Brian Ward Salt, Fat, Acid, Heat: Mastering the Elements of Good Cooking, Samin Nosrat  Finished and Recommend  Don&amp;rsquo;t Make Me Think, Steve Krug Invisible Cities, Italo Calvino Deep Work, Cal Newport Increment Issue 11, &amp;ldquo;Teams&amp;rdquo; Eloquent JavaScript, 3rd Edition, Marjin Haverbeke The Mom Test, Rob Fitzpatrick The Soul of a New Machine, Tracy Kidder Meditations, Marcus Aurelius How to Solve It, George Pólya Circe, Madeline Miller Skin in the Game: Hidden Asymmetries in Daily Life, Nassim Nicholas Taleb The Lathe of Heaven, Ursula Le Guin Automate the Boring Stuff with Python, 2nd ed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://mattdrake.dev/fixed/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 19:30:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattdrake.dev/fixed/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Matt Drake. I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer in the Washington, D.C. metro area.
For fun, I like to design games, read, and see live music. You can also find me at baseball games, nerding out with my awesome wife. Go Nats!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>